Benchikh Abdelouahab Mefteh El-Kheir

| +213698830334 | am.benchikh@esi-sba.dz | linkedin.com/in/ouahabs | https://github.com/ouahabs

PROFILE

Benchikh Abdelouahab Mefteh El-Kheir, a 4-th year computer science student at the Higher School of Computer Science (ESI SBA), with a passion for cyber security, networking, computer science & technology, and everything in between.

I like to study objects to figure out their inner-workings, i enjoying research and delving deep into things.

EDUCATION

Higher School of Computer Science and Engineering (ESI SBA)

Sidi Bel Abbès, Algeria

Masters & Engineering Degree

Expected Graduation Date: 2024

- Enrolled in September 2019
- Top classes: System and Network Security, Advanced Networkings/Networking, Operating Systems, Databases, English

Baccalaureate Degree in Mathematics

Algeria

Highest Honors

Graduation Date: 2019

• Top classes: Mathematics, Physics

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, Golang, Javascript, PHP, C, Bash, x86 Assembly

DevOps: Docker, Git, Microsoft Azure

Other: Linux, Agile (Scrum), Slack, Jira, Trello

Communication: English (C2), French (C1), Arabic (mother tongue)

Career & Experience

Cyber Security Specialist

April – June 2023

Research & Development

Data Impact by NielsenIQ

- Research and implementation of anti-bot bypass solutions.
- De-obfuscation, encryption, and reverse engineering of web and mobile apps.
- We help companies with omni-channel e-commerce analytics about their products in **60 countries** across **+400 retailers**, with **+50 million products**.

Volunteer Intern

February 2023 – Present

Content Creator

Cyber Supply Drop & Noob Village

- Under the mentorship of Joshua Mason.
- Discord Administration, graphics, and content creation.
- We help give away cyber security training, resources, and certificates for those in need (Cyber Supply Drop)
- Training, and career advice (Noob Village)

CTF Player

April 2020 – Present

ShellSec

Capture The Flag Competitions ("habs")

- Currently a member of the ShellSec team.
- Various 1st place, 2nd and 3rd place finishes in international and country-wide CTFs.

Intern

September – October 2022

Algérie Telecom

Networking and Infrastructure Security

- Contributed to the maintenance of the IT infrastructure.
- Troubleshot various IT and help desk problems.
- Helped resolve a budget issue

Lead Graphic Designer

August 2021 – August 2022

 $Design \ \ \mathcal{E} \ \ Multimedia \ \ Department \ \ Manager$

Shellmates Club (ESI ex. INI)

- Managed a department of over 70 people.
- Created and contributed to various club event identities.
- Mentored and taught graphic design basics to junior student.

Huawei ICT Competition Global First Prize Winner

April 2023

Networking, Security, WLAN

Shenzhen, China

- First prize, among 70+, handling security and routing (firewalls, routing protocols, VPN, etc).
- Ranked in the top 6 (4th) in the regional phase, among the best teams in North Africa.
- Top 13 (individually) best in the national phase, from 2600 participants from across Algeria.

AlphaCTF February 2022

Alphabit Club

Online/on-site, teams (ESI SBA)

- Participated with ShellSec team.
- Finished in 1st place.
- Solved most Forensic and Web challenges.

IngeHack CTF June 2021

Ingeniums Club

Online/on-site, teams (ESI SBA)

- Participated with ShellSec team.
- Finished in 1st place.
- · Solved most Forensic and Web challenges.

Algeria National Cybersecurity CTF 2020

August 2020

CyberTalents

Online, teams

- Participated with DirtyBit team
- Finished in 6th place.

Quals: Jordan Algeria, Lebanon, Morocco National CTF 2020

July 2020

CyberTalents

Online, individual

- First ever CTF competition
- Finished in **3rd place** among the best players in the country.
- Solved all challenges, including Web, Reverse Engineering, Crypto, and Forensics

CERTIFICATES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador

April 2023

New Established Ambassador

Microsoft

- Profile can be viewed here
- Will be helping students learn and use Microsoft T technologies to prepare them for the professional life.

HCIA Datacom February 2023

Certified ICT Associate

Huawei

- Certificate can be viewed here
- Technologies and protocols in data communication, including routing & switching, firewalls, VPNs, and Wi-Fi technologies.
- Huawei solutions (SD-WAN, SDN, etc).

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

February 2023

AZ-900

Microsoft

- Certificate can be viewed here
- Azure technologies and services (storage, computing, security and compliance, etc.)

Python for Everybody

April 2020

Coursera

Python

- Certificate
- Used techniques for web scraping, API interaction, and Data visualisation

English Proficiency Certificate

January 2023

C2 Proficient

EFSET (CEFR Standard)

- Certificate can be viewed here
- 83/100 score (equivalent to 95-120 (TOEFL) or 8.0-9.0 (IELTS)

Edge-Based DL Cancer Diagnostics

February 2022 - June 2022

Open VINO, Deep Learning, Intel Neural Compute Stick

School Project

- Fine tuned OpenVINO model to detect cancerous (and benign) masses in x-ray images
- Recieved an B+ grade.

Madrasatic

February 2022 - June 2022

Laravel, Javascript

 $School\ Project$

- Contributed to the back-end, and REST API portions of the project.
- Worked in an Agile (scrum) environment with 6 people.
- Recieved an B+ grade.

Athena Mars 2021

PHP, JS, HTML, CSS, Arduino, Java

School Project

- Mobile/Web applications for real-time tracking of several metrics (temperature, humidity, etc.), of delivered goods
- Contributed to the backend, while working in a team of 6.
- Created the live interactive map section, with PHP and Javascript.
- Recieved an A+ grade.

Inge-Neer Event Platform

December 2021

Laravel, LiveWire, React.js

Club Project

- Platform for the Inge-Neer event by Ingeniums Club
- Contributed to the creation of challenges, as well as the back-end with a team of 4 people.

Additional Information

- My **TryHackMe** and **HackTheBox** profiles, where I have solved more than 50 rooms and 10 boxes, and still counting.
- For more information, please feel free to contact me through any of my aforementioned contact information, or through my **website**